Michael J Stokes

Front End Developer

Ph: 336.693.5580

Email: michael@mjstokes.com

GitHub: github.com/mjstokes86 GitLab: gitlab.com/mjstokes86 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/mjstokes1

Portfolio: mjstokes.com

Profile

Hello! I know you're busy, so here's what you need to know about me in one sentence:

The job opportunity stands out to me; I'm a front end developer ready to work for you. I have over 4 years of working experience and the eagerness to learn new technologies, I am self motivated, and I enjoy taking on challenges that will help solve bigger and better problems.

Technology

Programming Languages + Frameworks: JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, jQuery, Node JS, Express, Mustache, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap | Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3 | Version Control: Git/GitHub

Experience

Front End Development Consultant - 2015-present

Front End development serving a global client base.

- Developed and consulted on disparate web presence initiatives utilizing a Front End toolset which included JavaScript, Ruby, Node, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, and WordPress.
- Provided responsive, clean design taking full advantage of flexibility within rails template engines, Bootstrap, and stock photography.
- Engaged in timeline negotiation, feature review and release timing, and change control. Held regular meetings with the customer as it related to status, roadblocks, and timing.
- Customized WordPress themes using different plugins where I personally added custom HTML/CSS elements and PHP code to function the entire site per client's needs.
- Optimized image sizes and quality for web using Photoshop.
- Created custom modules in WordPress that implement design mock-ups, comply with responsive design specs, and conform to coding standards.

Client List

NLM Marketing - (http://nlm-marketing.herokuapp.com/)
Method Savvy - (https://www.mindpointgroup.com/)

Front End Developer, Plum Direct Marketing; Remote - May 2019—September 2019

Created and built entire Wordpress websites from mockups serving the company clients

- Managed the Wordpress dashboard to maintain functionality of all sites.
- Performed quality control testing on all live websites to ensure proper maintenance.
- Customized themes and templates using Wordpress Elementor to provide satisfactory appearance.

Front End Developer, uStadium; Remote - April 2017-June 2017

Translated PSD files to responsive HTML/CSS and JavaScript for the development of the new company site.

- Solely responsible for the development of the company new site and provided responsiveness with a clean design.
- Provided PSD to HTML5/CSS3 translations from the UI/UX designs. Engaged in the client side of the development process to ensure proper functionality.
- Worked closely with the CEO and lead developer to ensure proper site functionality.
- Created RESTful services in JavaScript Node and Express that syncs the live JSON data source into the web application.

Front End Developer, Spin A Web Designs; Jamestown, NC - February 2017-April 2017

Developed varied web presence assets for clients of Spin-A-Web Designs using HTML, and CSS.

- Assisted with initial customer negotiation relative to expectation, timelines, and establishing cadence for reporting.
- Engaged in pair-programming with client-side developers to ensure continuity and knowledge transfer for specific functionality.
- Documented code, site functionality, and architecture in support of a "warm hand off" with the customer.

Recent Projects

Name That Tube (https://namethattube.herokuapp.com)

A Ruby on Rails based trivia game where users test their knowledge of music, games, TV and movies via targeted YouTube videos.

- Built the game-flow logic including PSQL queries to store a user's progress.
- Created answer-checking functionality using HTML forms and ActiveRecord queries.
- Built HTML forms that render game content provided by the the controllers and database with embedded Ruby.

Music Forum (http://music-forum.herokuapp.com)

A JavaScript Node/Express application that allows users to post music relative to specific topics and comment according to personal interests.

- Developed a home grown JavaScript CRUD system within the application that allows users to easily manage content.
- Developed SQLite queries that sync specific data into the views with the use of Mustache.

New York City Quiz (https://nycreactquiz.herokuapp.com)

A JavaScript React application that allows potential New Yorkers which borough they belong to based on their personalities.

- Created different components for easy organization to function each part of the quiz application
- -Developed a custom API that sets the quiz questions and answers which determines the final result

Education

General Assembly, New York, NY - Web Development Immersive, 2015 Johnson & Wales University, Charlotte, NC - Associate's, Merchandising, 2006

References

References and select client list available upon request.